ALEJANDRO SABOGAL

954-261-1961 | ASABOGAL, DEV @GMAIL, COM | ALEJANDRO-SABOGAL, COM GITHUB | LINKEDIN | BLOG

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Alejandro is a full-stack developer proficient in Ruby (Rails and Sinatra), JavaScript, React and Redux. A quick learner with a passion for knowledge and problem solving, he has experience in several industries including Banking and Finance, Hospitality, and Audio Engineering, complemented with strong familiarity in Entrepreneurship and Business Development.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

(full portfolio available at ALEJANDRO-SABOGAL.COM)

RECORDBOX REVIEWS - Try It | GitHub Repo | Demo

*This project was featured as a student project highlight on Flatiron School's Newsletter! Maintains the user's vinyl record collection (or Recordbox) and allows interaction with other users

- **Employed** Ruby on Rails Framework to create an MVC CRUD application.
- Provided user authentication through Bcrypt Gem, as well as via OmniAuth-Facebook.
- Designed front-end with Bootstrap

INTERVAL-TRAINING-TIMER - Try It | GitHub Repo | Demo

Customizable High-Intensity-Interval-Training Timer

- Implemented React and Redux to render a single-page application for web and mobile
- Augmented functionality to POST and GET presets and user settings on a Rails back-end API
- **Styled** front-end with 'reactstrap'

UEFA SCHEDULES - Try It | GitHub Repo | Demo

Get previous, future, and up to the minute European league soccer matches

- Consumes a third-party API and renders data dynamically via AJAX and JSON
- Generated service objects to manage the third-party API responses and control the app's main logic
- Developed a dual application functionality application; Rails API together with HTML rendering
- Translated JSON responses from Rails API into JavaScript Model Objects using ES6 class syntax

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript React/Redux Ruby Ruby on Rails Sinatra SQL HTML/CSS JQuery

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

ProTools Ableton Live Logic Pro Various Audio Plugins Hardware Syntheses Mac OSX

LANGUAGES

English Spanish

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER PROGRAM | New York, NY

Over 1000 hours of coursework, labs, and personal projects

SAE Institute of Technology - AUDIO ENGINEER DEGREE | Miami, FL

Ranked at the top 1% of the class; graduated with a 3.9 GPA

Florida International University - BACHELOR IN FINANCE FROM THE COLLEGE OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION | Miami, FL

Dean's List

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

BUSINESS CONSULTANT - CR Properties/Gallery Hotels LLC | New York, NY | August 2016 - Present

- Business Consultant for the company's Real Estate Properties and Hotel & Restaurant operations.
- Developed and actualized new business strategies and logistics leading to a 73% increase in revenues from previous year.

AUDIO MIXER/SOUND ENGINEER - The Kitchen Studios | Miami, FL | January 2011 - February 2016

- Audio processing and rendering on digital and analogue consoles
- Troubleshoot and maintained digital audio workstations

CO-FOUNDER/OWNER - PLOT Bookings | Miami, FL | December 2007 - December 2014

- Co-founder of a top music event production series and promotion outfits in the United States
- Event Promotions, nightlife culture, and international artist booking company
- Responsible for Management, A&R, Marketing/Social Media, Finance, and live sound coordination

PRIVATE BANKER - Bank of America Private Bank/Banc of America Investments | Miami, FL | January 2007 - December 2008

Assistant to the National Sales Manager of the International Wealth Management Group and head of the Miami's International Private Bank office.